iup.edu 2016-06-16

# Privacy Statement - Privacy - Indiana University of Pennsylvania

## Our Use of Cookies

The Indiana University of Pennsylvania (IUP) website uses [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/ "Google Analytics") to help analyze how users use the site. The Foundation for IUP serves as the registrant for Google products and acts as IUP’s agent for Google products. This analytical tool uses cookies, which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous manner. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors’ use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.

IUP will not (and will not allow any third party) to use this statistical analytics tool to collect or track any personally identifiable information about visitors to our site. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source as part of our use of Google Analytics. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither IUP nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user.

### Further Information about Cookies

The [About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies website"), maintained by law firm Pinsent Masons, explains how to delete and control the cookies stored on your computer. Additional information about cookies is available via [Google](http://www.google.com/search?q=define:Cookie&oi=glossary_definition "Google") and [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie "Wikipedia").

### Disabling and Enabling Cookies

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings on your browser. The About Cookies site explains [how to remove cookies from your browser](http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-delete-cookies/ "how to remove cookies from your browser").

## Using our Search Engine

Our search engine is powered by a piece of hardware supplied by Google (a Google Mini). The Google hardware indexes our site using the same algorithms used by google.com. All search requests on our main website are handled by the Google Mini, and no search information is passed to any third party (including Google).

## Find People/On-Line Directory Service

Our [on-line directory service](http://search.people.iup.edu/ "Find People") provides only personal information that has been authorized by those listed.

At your request, your address information can be changed, restricted, or removed from the on-line directory. Employees should contact the Office of Human Resources; students can change their information by logging into URSA.

## On-Line Forms

Information entered into on-line forms on this website (aside from search forms) may be delivered to its recipients by e-mail. E-mail is not a secure form of communication, and it is possible, though unlikely, that your information could be intercepted and read by a third party while in transit.

If you do not feel comfortable with the possibility of your information being intercepted by a third party, please feel free to contact the appropriate office by mail or by phone. Contact information is provided at the bottom of every page on the site.

## Family Education Rights and Privacy Act

IUP is bound by federal law—the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)—to protect the privacy of its students. Any personal information collected by this website is protected by university policy.
